Austen Tucker-Crowder

austen.crowder@gmail.com 6121 N Sheridan Rd. #2h, Chicago, IL 60660 1-317-410-7271

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Multitalented scrum master, business analyst, javascript developer, and project manager with eleven years of experience in government, finance, telecom, and housing. She is most at home in environments that allow her to utilize a unique, out-of-the-box skillset as techie, teacher, servant leader, and creative person to devise elegant solutions to inelegant problems.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Complete agile and waterfall software development lifecycle experience in tightly regulated business and government environments
- Agile coach and mentor for multiple teams with both remote and on-site members
- Planning messaging, approach, and market strategy for proposals, software demonstrations, and team presentations with C-suite executives, SMEs and other stakeholders
- Generating documentation including user stories, use cases, gap analyses, business needs assessments, test plans, training materials, and helpdesk documentation
- Production work with javascript, bootstrap, angular, jquery, and postgres
- Experience with clojure
- Tracking software: Google Analytics, Hotjar, Datadog, Grafana
- Google Analytics IQ certified
- Work Tracking software: Jira, Confluence, Trello
- CSM

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Guaranteed Rate, Chicago, Illinois

Scrummaster and Project Lead, November 2015 to Present

Scrummaster for multiple, autonomous backend development teams working in postgres, redis, angular, clojure, and bootstrap. Team deliverable included a data mining tool that generated \$1.5B in locked loans and Gateless, a portal targeting realtors.

- Scrum master duties for two teams (total of ~15 engineers at any one time). Managed process; ran ceremonies including retro, demo, and standup; and removed blockers for developers.
- Took on a cross-team, two-year initiative for app package generation that had stalled prior to delivery. Worked with engineers to rescope the project, define clear milestones, and communicate to executives the blockers and risks that threatened project delivery. Once rebased the project delivered an MVP within two months and reduced time to create app packages by 75%.
- Worked as product owner for a lead generation initiative, fielding user requests, collecting feedback, and showing the impact of our work to C-suite executives with metrics and user testimonials. The initiative garnered ~\$1.5B of loan lock volume in the course of three months.
- Coached business stakeholders in agile project management principles to help manage expectations and encourage closer collaboration between tech and business.
- Worked with business stakeholders to develop a measurement plan for Gateless, a web app designed to help realtors and referral partners, using Google Analytics and Hotjar. Metrics helped the team make a case for removing features that were used by < 1% of visitors.
- Wrote and deployed javascript/bootstrap google maps app showing live business data to help drive adoption of a business initiative.
- Gave presentations to C-suite executives on team successes, progress, and roadmap items.

Chicago Housing Authority, Chicago, Illinois

Project Manager and Business Analyst, October 2012 to October 2015

Senior Business Analyst and Scrum Master for a small, in-house .NET development team. The Chicago Housing Authority is the largest renter in the city of Chicago; applications created and maintained for the authority aided business users in tracking over 30,000 participants and 250,000 waitlist participants in multiple programs in a highly regulated environment.

- Performed an agile transformation within the IT department to limit scope creep and better manage user expectations. Reduced turn time on feature requests from two months to two weeks.
- Lead BA for a \$7M contract with external developers for an enterprise-wide ECM system and workflow engine. Responsibilities included use case validation, gap analysis, and UAT design. Resulting system handles Recertification, Intake, and Transfers jobs for 30,000 participants.
- Acted as project manager, BA, and UX designer for a flexible, online job application system mandated by HUD for low-income Chicago residents.
- Generated presentations and messaging strategy to get buy-in from resident councils, political appointees, and senior-level executives.

Technology Partnership Group, Indianapolis, Indiana

Business Analyst, May 2009 to September 2012

Discovered patterns, gaps, and creative solutions to problems that arose in implementations of EnABLE, a municipal loan and bond management system. Became a SME on complex Clean Water Act financial programs. Team worked within Agile environment to quickly establish goals, requirements, and development in accelerated time frames. Current implementations of EnABLE handle loan portfolios more than \$300M apiece.

- Arranged end-user focus group testing to discover enhancements not previously conceived.
 Resulting product enhancements were cited by clients as justification to skip official government procurement processes.
- Lead gap analysis activities during implementation with accounting, developer, and system administration teams to match client business practices to software functionality.
- Conceived the user interface, functionality, and documentation for EnABLE.
- Performed proposal writing activities for government RFPs including research, content development, editing, messaging, and layout. Successful bids based on proposals generated revenue in excess of \$1MM over the course of two years.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Bell Techlogix, Indianapolis, Indiana: Call Center Analyst, February 2009 to May 2009
AOTMP, Indianapolis, Indiana: Telecom Research Writer, September 2008 to February 2009
Cardinal Ritter High School, Indianapolis, Indiana: 10th Grade English Teacher, August 2007 to June 2008

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION

Wabash College, Cum Laude, English and Teacher Education Certified Scrummaster

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Published Novelist: Bait and Switch, The Painted Cat